<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="qryFactsXMLYearOne.xsd" generated="2009-08-17T15:18:51">
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>127</ID>
<FactID>4000089</FactID>
<ReferenceID>N/A</ReferenceID>
<Generic>true</Generic>
<Description>Director Harold Ramis hired two long time collaborators, Gene Stupinsky and Lee Eisenberg, to help him write the script for YEAR ONE. Both are writers and executive producers for the American version of &quot;The Office.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>YEAR ONE</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>128</ID>
<FactID>4000090</FactID>
<ReferenceID>N/A</ReferenceID>
<Generic>true</Generic>
<Description>Construction of the set for the City of Sodom covered five acres in northeastern Louisiana. It was so large, it was the equivalent of 46 sets, yet its construction was completed in only 10 weeks.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>YEAR ONE</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>129</ID>
<FactID>4000091</FactID>
<ReferenceID>N/A</ReferenceID>
<Generic>true</Generic>
<Description>Production Designer Jefferson Sage had worked with both Harold Ramis (ANALYZE THIS) and Judd Apatow (THE TV SET, KNOCKED UP, WALK HARD: THE DEWEY COX STORY) prior to his work on YEAR ONE</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>YEAR ONE</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>130</ID>
<FactID>4000092</FactID>
<ReferenceID>N/A</ReferenceID>
<Generic>true</Generic>
<Description>Producer Judd Apatow felt privileged to work with one of his childhood idols, Harold Ramis. Apatow says, &quot;Some of the highlights of my childhood were the days when I went with my friends to see STRIPES, GHOSTBUSTERS, CADDYSHACK and ANIMAL HOUSE. It has been a real honor to get to see him work up close.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Judd Apatow</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>131</ID>
<FactID>4000093</FactID>
<ReferenceID>N/A</ReferenceID>
<Generic>true</Generic>
<Description>In addition to producing the film, Judd Apatow and his extended writing team helped to hone the script for YEAR ONE. Director Harold Ramis claims as many as 17 writers worked under Apatow&apos;s lead during the final stages of scriptwriting.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>YEAR ONE</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>132</ID>
<FactID>4000094</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000225</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Jack Black had an appreciation for his skunk pelt costume in early scenes. Says Black, &quot;I think that was the most inspired costume – all the other hunters have bear hides and wolf coats. I just got my stinky skunk pelt. That’s what Zed was able to hunt down and capture. It says a lot about my character.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>133</ID>
<FactID>4000095</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000227</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Despite the outlandish nature of the film, Production Designer Jefferson Sage opted to create sets that closely mirrored what the characters would have experienced in YEAR ONE.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>134</ID>
<FactID>4000096</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000228</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Jack Black was not a fan of the albino python in this scene, choosing to stay as far away as possible from it during shooting. When the python appears to be wrapped around Michael Cera&apos;s head, it is actually a rubber python that was animated during post production.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.movieretriever.com/blog/368/interview-with-harold-ramis-year-one</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>135</ID>
<FactID>4000097</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000229</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The filmmakers used distinct color palettes and settings to set one location apart from the next. Says Production Designer Jefferson Sage, &quot;For example, in the Paleolithic village, one of the rules is there’s no metal because at that time, these guys haven’t discovered metal yet.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>136</ID>
<FactID>4000098</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000232</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Michael Cera&apos;s character was given his name for a specific reason. Director Harold Ramis says, &quot;We called this character ‘Oh’ because he’s completely reacting to life and everything in life that is a threat to his character -- and he does suffer a lot in the movie,”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Michael Cera</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>137</ID>
<FactID>4000099</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000234</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Jack Black was Director Harold Ramis&apos; first choice to play Zed. Says Ramis, &quot;The whole time, I was thinking, ‘Wow, this could be great for Jack Black. Jack really knows how to be silly and take big chances with comedy&apos;.&quot; </Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Jack Black</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>138</ID>
<FactID>4000100</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000236</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Filmmakers considered several ways to portray the farming society of Cain and Abel. Production Designer Jonathan Sage says, &quot;We ultimately opted for a Neolithic European longhouse design, because Harold didn&apos;t like the original round houses we were thinking about. Both designs were right out of the history books.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>139</ID>
<FactID>4000101</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000238</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>David Cross had worked with both Jack Black (MR. SHOW WITH BOB AND DAVID) and Michael Cera (ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT) prior to filming YEAR ONE.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>David Cross</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>140</ID>
<FactID>4000102</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000241</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>David Cross very much enjoyed his role as Cain. Says Cross, &quot;It’s very much fun to play a guy who doesn’t have any morals and is manipulative and threatening. He’s just a nasty guy.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>David Cross</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>141</ID>
<FactID>4000103</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000243</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The desert scenes were filmed at the White Sands National Monument in New Mexico. Several other productions, including 1996&apos;s INDEPENDENCE DAY, have also filmed there.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>142</ID>
<FactID>4000104</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000245</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Director Harold Ramis was excited to work with Christopher Mintz-Platz. Says Ramis, &quot;After seeing SUPERBAD, it was an irresistible temptation to make Christopher the whiny, complaining son of Abraham. He just seemed perfect for the part.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Christopher Mintz-Platz</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>143</ID>
<FactID>4000105</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000246</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Harold Ramis had a unique notion for the character of Abraham played by Hank Azaria. Says Ramis, &quot;Way back when, George C. Scott played Abraham in a John Huston film called THE BIBLE. I had this notion of getting Hank Azaria playing George C. Scott playing Abraham.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Hank Azaria</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>144</ID>
<FactID>4000106</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000248</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Christopher Mintz-Platz could not see for much of the filming. Says Mintz-Platz, &quot;...you can&apos;t wear glasses in YEAR ONE, they didn&apos;t exist. And I didn&apos;t have my contacts at the time, so I had to film the whole movie-like-blind as a bat.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Christopher Mintz-Platz</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://en.terra.com/entertainment/articles/html/oci16824.htm</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>145</ID>
<FactID>4000107</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000247</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The scenes featuring Abraham&apos;s camp were shot on location at Georgia O&apos;Keefe&apos;s Ghost Ranch in Abiquiu, New Mexico. Production designers modeled the Hebrew camps of Abraham after other film&apos;s representations of them, rather than striving for historical accuracy.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>146</ID>
<FactID>4000108</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000252</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Production designers relied on historical precedent and their own sense of style to create the city of Sodom. Production Designer Jefferson Sage says, &quot;We looked at fortified cities from similar periods and studied details about them, and then we put those together into our own kind of vision of Sodom.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>147</ID>
<FactID>4000109</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000249</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>When Zed and Oh first encounter the city of Sodom, they come upon its fortified yet unadorned walls.  Filmmakers took inspiration for the look and feel of the city of Sodom from Dura Europos, a Roman city located in what is now Syria.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>148</ID>
<FactID>4000110</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000250</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Vinnie Jones, here playing Sargon, was well known in England as a soccer player before starting his acting career. He appeared in over 380 matches from 1986 to 1999 and had a reputation for aggressive play, a trait which he brings to many of his acting roles.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Vinnie Jones</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vinnie_Jones</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>149</ID>
<FactID>4000111</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000269</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Costume designer Debra McGuire tried to make the actor&apos;s attire as accurate as possible. Says McGuire, &quot;You have to let the comedy be the comedy. We can never try to make clothes funny and distracting.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>Fact</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>Costume Designer Debra McGuire</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>150</ID>
<FactID>4000112</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000254</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>As with each set, costume designers also designed individual palettes for different groups of the cast. Costumer Designer Debra McGuire says, &quot;I took the priest cast and divided them into these beautiful lush purples and raspberry colors. For the ministers and all the people below, I came up with a palette very cinnamon and persimmon.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>Fact</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>151</ID>
<FactID>4000113</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000256</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>There were many idols present at the time of YEAR ONE, but production designers liked the visual impact of a bull. Production designer Jefferson Sage says, &quot;…it seemed like the bull, with its commanding, domineering face, made sense dramatically.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>152</ID>
<FactID>4000114</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000259</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Production designer Jefferson Sage was looking for an appropriate motif for the orgy scene and found it in ancient Egypt. He says, &quot;To create the scene for these nightly orgies, we wanted to create a very sensuous architecture. And ancient Egyptian art and architecture is about the most sensuous I know.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>153</ID>
<FactID>4000115</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000260</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Michael Cera quickly discovered the pains of being painted gold. Says Cera, &quot;Getting painted gold was the most uncomfortable thing I’ve ever done for a job. It was awful. And it took forever to get it off – I’d take several showers and then still see gold on my ankles.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>154</ID>
<FactID>4000116</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000262</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The actors in YEAR ONE demonstrated a great deal of range with their accents. British actress Juno Temple delivered a convincing American accent while American actors Oliver Platt and Olivia Wilde gave their best British impression.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Juno Temple</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>155</ID>
<FactID>4000117</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000264</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Filmmakers used their set design to drive home key points of the story. Production Designer Jefferson Sage says, &quot;We used all these rich tapestries to express the idea that instead of governing well Sodom&apos;s leaders are using their money on decoration of the highest level of sophistication.&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>156</ID>
<FactID>4000118</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000265</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The crown worn by Oliver Platt was designed to convey the sense of grandeur that the High Priest embodies. Costumer Designer Debra McGuire says, &quot;He wears a crown with three levels of opulence. Not only is it completely jeweled, but my idea was that all of the priests under him would have a lower level of crown.&quot;&quot;</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Oliver Platt</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>157</ID>
<FactID>4000119</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000268</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Michael Cera endured many physical hardships during the making of YEAR ONE including hanging upside down in this scene. Says Cera, &quot;There’s another point in the movie where I’m hanging upside down; I thought that was bad, but I’d do that in a heartbeat over getting painted gold again.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Michael Cera</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>158</ID>
<FactID>4000120</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000270</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>The wardrobe department for YEAR ONE also created period-accurate attire for over 100 extras along with their work for the cast.</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>159</ID>
<FactID>4000121</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000271</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Actress Olivia Wilde felt liberated in her role as Princess Ianna. She says, &quot;Trying to win the hearts and minds of the audience can hold you back from taking risks. I felt free to go over the top and make Ianna as ridiculous as I could imagine.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>CONTRIBUTOR</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Olivia Wilde</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>160</ID>
<FactID>4000122</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000272</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Director Harold Ramis cites an improvisation he staged with Bill Murray as a &quot;Modern&quot; Cro-Magnon man as inspiration for YEAR ONE. Says Ramis, &quot;...I had those inspirations in mind when I thought it would be really interesting to put someone with a contemporary consciousness in an ancient setting.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>161</ID>
<FactID>4000123</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000273</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Construction during the time of YEAR ONE was a dangerous business. Production Designer Jefferson Sage says, &quot;...We tried to convey that in the scaffolding around the ziggurat, which is just put together with twine. That helps makes the scene were Zed brings it all crashing down.&quot; </Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.archaeology.org/online/reviews/yearone/</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
<qryFactsXML>
<ID>162</ID>
<FactID>4000124</FactID>
<ReferenceID>3000277</ReferenceID>
<Generic>false</Generic>
<Description>Director Harold Ramis found inspiration in the humankind&apos;s innate longing during the writing process. He says, &quot;...no matter how far back we went, we would find that people were driven by the same needs and had the same potential awareness. I’m convinced that there had to  be a hunter/gatherer thinking, ”There’s got to be more to life than this&apos;.”</Description>
<FactReferenceType>FACT</FactReferenceType>
<FactReferenceID>Fact</FactReferenceID>
<Source1>http://www.wildaboutmovies.com/behind_the_scenes/YearOne-BEHINDTHESCENES.php</Source1>
</qryFactsXML>
</dataroot>
